<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Mutt0-ds Notes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Mutt0-ds Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Second Brain... 6 Months later: Obsidian update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/09/obsidian-update-6-months-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/09/obsidian-update-6-months-later/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been quite the journey since I first delved into Second Brain technologies for organizing my team&amp;rsquo;s documentation. I previously shared my initial experiences with Obsidian, and now, it&amp;rsquo;s time for a comprehensive update. In case you missed my earlier exploration, you can catch up here.&#xA;So, what has changed? Let&amp;rsquo;s dive right in. Since my last update, I&amp;rsquo;ve continued to utilize Obsidian for secure and structured note organization within my team, enjoying the rapid and intuitive process and enjoying its advantages (flexibility, powerful search system, security, and so on).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal Notes about Simply Said</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/07/personal-notes-simply-said/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/07/personal-notes-simply-said/</guid>
      <description>Simply Said Simply Said is the best communication book I&amp;rsquo;ve recently read. It consdes so much information that it resembles an encyclopedia, and the beatufiul thoing is that its key point is, simply said, &amp;ldquo;focus on others&amp;rdquo;. So, for the others, as you, I ocnsodnere the 19 chapters of this useful guide by Jy Sullivan in an easy-to graps blog post,m which will giver you a general overviwew, and hopegully, th deisre to by it .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing Productivity with Obsidian: My Second Brain for Organizing Work Notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/02/obsidian-productivity-second-brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/02/obsidian-productivity-second-brain/</guid>
      <description>🧠 Introduction to Second Brains &amp;amp; Brain Dumping As I&amp;rsquo;m working with data all the time, I&amp;rsquo;m aware of the importance of keeping it in a safe and structured place, where it can be easily accessed when needed, which could be days, weeks or even years in the future. Thus, organizing my information, tasks, and notes is a key activity in my work (and personal) life. Without a clear system, I would feel lost in chaos, and my productivity would plunge (also considering that my memory sucks).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal Notes about Presentation Patterns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/01/personal-notes-about-presentation-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/01/personal-notes-about-presentation-patterns/</guid>
      <description>Presentation Patterns Written by Neal Ford, Matthew McCullough and Nathaniel Schutta, &amp;ldquo;Presentation Patterns - Techniques for Crafting Better Presentations&amp;rdquo; is an encyclopedia of patterns, tips and common mistakes experienced by the authors, who have delivered thousands of presentations. In particular, they introduce “No Fluff, Just Stuff“, a traveling technical conference series covering a wide variety of topics related to software development and management.&#xA;During the years, they have build up their toolbox of patterns to provide killer presentations, which are divided in three main sections: Prepare (thinking and setting up the presentation’s key concepts), Build (creating the slides), Deliver (present the content).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal Notes about The Definitive Guide to DAX</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/09/personal-notes-about-dax-definitive-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/09/personal-notes-about-dax-definitive-guide/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: this will be a long, long post, written in my own way. It’s essentially a dump of my personal notes, taken when reading “The Definitive Guide to DAX” written by Alberto Ferrari and Marco Russo. At my new workplace I’m going to use PowerBI and DAX a lot, thus my boss suggested me to read the book.&#xA;Yep, it is big and very technical, with 700+ pages rich in contents, but trust me, that’s the “Bible”, a must-read for anyone willing to work with PowerBI and DAX.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
