<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure on Mutt0-ds Notes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/azure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure on Mutt0-ds Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My AI-tweaked Data Saturdays 23 Notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/11/ai-tweaked-data-saturdays-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/11/ai-tweaked-data-saturdays-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Saturday I had the privilege of attending &lt;a href=&#34;https://datasaturdays.com/2023-11-18-datasaturday0037/&#34;&gt;Data Saturdays #37 at Parma&lt;/a&gt;, an event series focused on Microsoft data platform technologies. Covering AI, Database, Business Intelligence, and Cloud, the event promised insights from top experts in Italy (and beyond).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course, I wrote down (almost) everything I heard.&#xA;This blog post is actually a dump of my notes, which I tried to partially automated with a mix of OCR + ChatGPT, which struggled in understanding most of the complex contexts&amp;hellip; My disorganized note management didn&amp;rsquo;t help, poor GPT.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A turbulent journey through Power BI source control</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/11/turbulent-journey-power-bi-source-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/11/turbulent-journey-power-bi-source-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most annoying issues I have when working with Power BI files is that source control is a real pain.&#xA;Considering that Microsoft owns Azure, Github, and Power BI, one would hope that they will come up with a solution for comparing two reports without using third-party tools or overly complicated solutions&amp;hellip; But that day seems still far in the future.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here is a story about how I managed to set up a CI/CD pipeline through Azure DevOps Pipeline for providing rudimental version control of our Power BI reports.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My first weeks at Acer Europe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/10/first-weeks-acer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/10/first-weeks-acer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a post for my future self when I will be asking myself: &lt;em&gt;“How were my first days at Acer like?”&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Note: I&amp;rsquo;m working at Acer EMEA HQ, so when I mention &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Acer&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;, for simplicity, I mean &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Acer Europe&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;-my-expectations&#34;&gt;💭 My expectations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My previous experience was in a small company and a very different sector. Considering this, I was expecting the following challenges in the upcoming scenario:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An organization with thousands of employees and decades of history&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Several departments and key stakeholders to interact with, each one with specific priorities&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A huge IT department where I&amp;rsquo;m the youngest member here&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;New technologies to discover: in particular, I&amp;rsquo;ve never worked with most of the Azure tools we are using&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A whole new level of complexity&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too worried about the previous points, as I&amp;rsquo;m happy to learn new things and I&amp;rsquo;m used to managing projects with different stakeholders. Being a &lt;strong&gt;Business Intelligence Developer&lt;/strong&gt;, my tasks were going to be about managing Power BI dashboards and collecting data from databases, more or less what I was used to doing before&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
