<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dax on Mutt0-ds Notes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/dax/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dax on Mutt0-ds Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/dax/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Pro Trick for Measure Descriptions in Power BI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/08/the-trick-measure-description-powerbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/08/the-trick-measure-description-powerbi/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;How does this MEASURE/COLUMN work?&amp;rdquo; This is one of the most frequent requests I was receiving. And it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see why.&#xA;In complex Power BI models, users often struggle to understand the meaning of specific measures or columns. This is especially true for ambiguous names like AMSLast12m or columns with deep business logic such as NetAmount. How is it calculated? With VAT? Without it? Help!&#xA;Traditionally, there were limited options: ask a colleague, guess the logic, search documentation, or simply try your luck and add it blindly to the report.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal Notes about The Definitive Guide to DAX</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/09/personal-notes-about-dax-definitive-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/09/personal-notes-about-dax-definitive-guide/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: this will be a long, long post, written in my own way. It’s essentially a dump of my personal notes, taken when reading “The Definitive Guide to DAX” written by Alberto Ferrari and Marco Russo. At my new workplace I’m going to use PowerBI and DAX a lot, thus my boss suggested me to read the book.&#xA;Yep, it is big and very technical, with 700+ pages rich in contents, but trust me, that’s the “Bible”, a must-read for anyone willing to work with PowerBI and DAX.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
