<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tabular-Editor on Mutt0-ds Notes</title>
    <link>https://mutt0-ds.github.io/tags/tabular-editor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tabular-Editor on Mutt0-ds Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mutt0-ds.github.io/tags/tabular-editor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Pro Trick for Measure Descriptions in Power BI</title>
      <link>https://mutt0-ds.github.io/posts/2024/08/the-trick-measure-description-powerbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mutt0-ds.github.io/posts/2024/08/the-trick-measure-description-powerbi/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;How does this MEASURE/COLUMN work?&amp;rdquo; This is one of the most frequent requests I was receiving. And it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see why.&#xA;In complex Power BI models, users often struggle to understand the meaning of specific measures or columns. This is especially true for ambiguous names like AMSLast12m or columns with deep business logic such as NetAmount. How is it calculated? With VAT? Without it? Help!&#xA;Traditionally, there were limited options: ask a colleague, guess the logic, search documentation, or simply try your luck and add it blindly to the report.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A turbulent journey through Power BI source control</title>
      <link>https://mutt0-ds.github.io/posts/2022/11/turbulent-journey-power-bi-source-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mutt0-ds.github.io/posts/2022/11/turbulent-journey-power-bi-source-control/</guid>
      <description>One of the most annoying issues I have when working with Power BI files is that source control is a real pain. Considering that Microsoft owns Azure, Github, and Power BI, one would hope that they will come up with a solution for comparing two reports without using third-party tools or overly complicated solutions&amp;hellip; But that day seems still far in the future.&#xA;Here is a story about how I managed to set up a CI/CD pipeline through Azure DevOps Pipeline for providing rudimental version control of our Power BI reports.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
