<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data-Analysis on Mutt0-ds Notes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/data-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data-Analysis on Mutt0-ds Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/data-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Finding the Best Time to Go to Work: Now with Car Accidents Data &amp; Power BI Dashboard!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/10/analyzing-accidents-data-to-perfectionize-my-commute/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/10/analyzing-accidents-data-to-perfectionize-my-commute/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to express my gratitude for the positive feedbacks I received a few months ago when &lt;a href=&#34;https://mutt0-ds.github.io/posts/2023/07/analyzing-commute-data-using-google-api/&#34;&gt;I used Google Maps data to determine the best times for the daily commute&lt;/a&gt;. TL;DR: Mondays are the best, while Wednesdays, and early Fridays are the trickiest times to hit the road.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, the neatness of this analysis takes a hit when real-world unpredictabilities come into play. Things like heavy traffic, rain, road closures due to accidents, or just that one slow driver in front of you can disrupt even the best-planned routes. So, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to view these explorations as &amp;ldquo;what if&amp;rdquo; games. They provide a general framework but can&amp;rsquo;t fully account for the chaos of everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing My Commute Data to Find the Best Time to Go to Work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/07/analyzing-commute-data-using-google-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/07/analyzing-commute-data-using-google-api/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When my commute buddy and I find ourselves stuck in traffic during our car journeys, we often daydream about finding the ideal route and &lt;strong&gt;the optimal time&lt;/strong&gt; to leave the office in order to avoid these uncomfortable situations. Now, thanks to the power of technology and the inspiration I drew from &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@hishamsajid113/using-google-distance-matrix-api-to-reduce-commute-time-b17a0b9b0fbe&#34;&gt;a fantastic article by @hishamsajid113&lt;/a&gt;, I am finally able to back up my theories about the best departure times from home and simulate with real data!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
