<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mutt0-ds Notes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mutt0-ds Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Pro Trick for Measure Descriptions in Power BI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/08/the-trick-measure-description-powerbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/08/the-trick-measure-description-powerbi/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;How does this MEASURE/COLUMN work?&amp;rdquo; This is one of the most frequent requests I was receiving. And it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see why.&#xA;In complex Power BI models, users often struggle to understand the meaning of specific measures or columns. This is especially true for ambiguous names like AMSLast12m or columns with deep business logic such as NetAmount. How is it calculated? With VAT? Without it? Help!&#xA;Traditionally, there were limited options: ask a colleague, guess the logic, search documentation, or simply try your luck and add it blindly to the report.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal Notes about Simply Said</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/07/personal-notes-simply-said/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/07/personal-notes-simply-said/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Simply Said&amp;rdquo; is the best communication book I&amp;rsquo;ve read recently. I discovered it thanks to Jordan Cutler (who runs an amazing tech newsletter) and at first, I considered it a standard communications book. Things like &amp;ldquo;listen to others,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;be positive,&amp;rdquo; blah blah.&#xA;I was wrong. &amp;ldquo;Simply Said&amp;rdquo; is much more than that. That&amp;rsquo;s why I condensed most of its wisdom into this blog post, and I hope it will inspire you to read it as well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giving our AI superpowers with OpenAI Tools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/06/ai-superpowers-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/06/ai-superpowers-tools/</guid>
      <description>In recent months, I have been experimenting with AI tools to leverage new, powerful technologies and create value. Like you, I am inundated with hype and buzzwords, and this makes things complicate, when trying to get started. While looking for simple answers to my questions, it’s often challenging to extract real value. So, I want to share my notes to help others with similar needs.&#xA;My Business Case: an AI Analyst Let’s start with the big question I had in my mind:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 3 (&#43;2) ways to Get Data in Power BI, simply explained</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/04/types-powerbi-connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/04/types-powerbi-connection/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s quite a bit of confusion swirling around about how Power BI reports gather data. Where is the data actually stored? How frequently does it refresh? Depending on the mode you&amp;rsquo;ve selected, this question can be a bit tricky to tackle.&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s simplify things a bit. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll be focusing on Power BI Desktop. Imagine you&amp;rsquo;ve got a .pbix file on hand and don&amp;rsquo;t quite have the time to sit through 10-minute technical video from Guy in a Cube that I usually link my users to.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My AI-tweaked Data Saturdays 23 Notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/11/ai-tweaked-data-saturdays-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/11/ai-tweaked-data-saturdays-notes/</guid>
      <description>Last Saturday I had the privilege of attending Data Saturdays #37 at Parma, an event series focused on Microsoft data platform technologies. Covering AI, Database, Business Intelligence, and Cloud, the event promised insights from top experts in Italy (and beyond).&#xA;Of course, I wrote down (almost) everything I heard. This blog post is actually a dump of my notes, which I tried to partially automated with a mix of OCR + ChatGPT, which struggled in understanding most of the complex contexts&amp;hellip; My disorganized note management didn&amp;rsquo;t help, poor GPT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding the Best Time to Go to Work: Now with Car Accidents Data &amp; Power BI Dashboard!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/10/analyzing-accidents-data-to-perfectionize-my-commute/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/10/analyzing-accidents-data-to-perfectionize-my-commute/</guid>
      <description>I want to express my gratitude for the positive feedbacks I received a few months ago when I used Google Maps data to determine the best times for the daily commute. TL;DR: Mondays are the best, while Wednesdays, and early Fridays are the trickiest times to hit the road.&#xA;However, the neatness of this analysis takes a hit when real-world unpredictabilities come into play. Things like heavy traffic, rain, road closures due to accidents, or just that one slow driver in front of you can disrupt even the best-planned routes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Second Brain... 6 Months later: Obsidian update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/09/obsidian-update-6-months-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/09/obsidian-update-6-months-later/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been quite the journey since I first delved into Second Brain technologies for organizing my team&amp;rsquo;s documentation. I previously shared my initial experiences with Obsidian, and now, it&amp;rsquo;s time for a comprehensive update. In case you missed my earlier exploration, you can catch up here.&#xA;So, what has changed? Let&amp;rsquo;s dive right in. Since my last update, I&amp;rsquo;ve continued to utilize Obsidian for secure and structured note organization within my team, enjoying the rapid and intuitive process and enjoying its advantages (flexibility, powerful search system, security, and so on).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing My Commute Data to Find the Best Time to Go to Work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/07/analyzing-commute-data-using-google-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/07/analyzing-commute-data-using-google-api/</guid>
      <description>When my commute buddy and I find ourselves stuck in traffic during our car journeys, we often daydream about finding the ideal route and the optimal time to leave the office in order to avoid these uncomfortable situations. Now, thanks to the power of technology and the inspiration I drew from a fantastic article by @hishamsajid113, I am finally able to back up my theories about the best departure times from home and simulate with real data!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The unnecessary hype strategy behind Microsoft Fabric</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/05/the-unnecessary-hype-fabric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/05/the-unnecessary-hype-fabric/</guid>
      <description>If you are into Data Engineering in Microsoft Azure Cloud Environment, you probaly heard about Microsoft Fabric being announced last week at the yearly event Microsoft Build. Well, &amp;ldquo;heard&amp;rdquo; is quite an euphesmism: everyone in the field is extremely excited about the announcements of the event. And for good reasons, as it’s a very big deal for us engineers, working with data every day.&#xA;In short, Fabric is a cutting-edge, unified data platform that merges lots of tools together, starting from a common Data Lake where data can be stored (OneLake), and a suite of new tools on top of it that are integrated in the “fabric” of Fabric.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I ended up with AI-generated Music Reviews on TikTok</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/05/how-i-generated-automatic-reviews-tiktok/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/05/how-i-generated-automatic-reviews-tiktok/</guid>
      <description>This is a fun story, with a series of technologies and topics that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t believe they were capable of living together&amp;hellip; EDM, TikTok, Text-To-Speech, AI, Playwright&amp;hellip; Many times, when going down this over-engineered rabbit hole, I thought, &amp;ldquo;OK, I have to write about this thing.&amp;rdquo; And also, &amp;ldquo;What am I doing here with my time?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;📚 Some context So, here are a few key things to be aware of:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Power BI is still missing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/03/what-power-bi-is-missing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/03/what-power-bi-is-missing/</guid>
      <description>During these months, I had the chance to take a look at Power BI at the enterprise level, juggling advanced requests from hundreds of users and reports. I am impressed by all the features that the developers have rolled out recently, greatly improving both user and creator experiences. However, one should always maintain an impartial critical vision of the tools, no matter how useful they can be. For this reason, I decided to share my thoughts about some features that are currently lacking or require over-complicated solutions (often from third-party tools), in the hope that Microsoft will find them useful when working on Power BI&amp;rsquo;s development roadmap.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing Productivity with Obsidian: My Second Brain for Organizing Work Notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/02/obsidian-productivity-second-brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/02/obsidian-productivity-second-brain/</guid>
      <description>🧠 Introduction to Second Brains &amp;amp; Brain Dumping As I&amp;rsquo;m working with data all the time, I&amp;rsquo;m aware of the importance of keeping it in a safe and structured place, where it can be easily accessed when needed, which could be days, weeks or even years in the future. Thus, organizing my information, tasks, and notes is a key activity in my work (and personal) life. Without a clear system, I would feel lost in chaos, and my productivity would plunge (also considering that my memory sucks).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal Notes about Presentation Patterns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/01/personal-notes-about-presentation-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/01/personal-notes-about-presentation-patterns/</guid>
      <description>Presentation Patterns Written by Neal Ford, Matthew McCullough and Nathaniel Schutta, &amp;ldquo;Presentation Patterns - Techniques for Crafting Better Presentations&amp;rdquo; is an encyclopedia of patterns, tips and common mistakes experienced by the authors, who have delivered thousands of presentations. In particular, they introduce “No Fluff, Just Stuff“, a traveling technical conference series covering a wide variety of topics related to software development and management.&#xA;During the years, they have build up their toolbox of patterns to provide killer presentations, which are divided in three main sections: Prepare (thinking and setting up the presentation’s key concepts), Build (creating the slides), Deliver (present the content).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Road to 100% Test Coverage on notion-sdk-py</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/12/road-100-coverage-notion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/12/road-100-coverage-notion/</guid>
      <description>There is something bizarre with me if two of my favourite activities are writing documentation and hitting my head against tests, which are notoriously unexciting activities for many developers 😫&#xA;Luckily, we are all unique in our own way and I decided to contribute to the testing module of one of my favorite libraries, notion-sdk-py.&#xA;Being a certified Notion user, I use its Web App on a daily basis, and the Python library helps me automatically organize my notes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A turbulent journey through Power BI source control</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/11/turbulent-journey-power-bi-source-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/11/turbulent-journey-power-bi-source-control/</guid>
      <description>One of the most annoying issues I have when working with Power BI files is that source control is a real pain. Considering that Microsoft owns Azure, Github, and Power BI, one would hope that they will come up with a solution for comparing two reports without using third-party tools or overly complicated solutions&amp;hellip; But that day seems still far in the future.&#xA;Here is a story about how I managed to set up a CI/CD pipeline through Azure DevOps Pipeline for providing rudimental version control of our Power BI reports.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My first weeks at Acer Europe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/10/first-weeks-acer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/10/first-weeks-acer/</guid>
      <description>This is a post for my future self when I will be asking myself: “How were my first days at Acer like?”.&#xA;Note: I&amp;rsquo;m working at Acer EMEA HQ, so when I mention &amp;ldquo;Acer&amp;rdquo;, for simplicity, I mean &amp;ldquo;Acer Europe&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;💭 My expectations My previous experience was in a small company and a very different sector. Considering this, I was expecting the following challenges in the upcoming scenario:&#xA;An organization with thousands of employees and decades of history Several departments and key stakeholders to interact with, each one with specific priorities A huge IT department where I&amp;rsquo;m the youngest member here New technologies to discover: in particular, I&amp;rsquo;ve never worked with most of the Azure tools we are using A whole new level of complexity I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too worried about the previous points, as I&amp;rsquo;m happy to learn new things and I&amp;rsquo;m used to managing projects with different stakeholders.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal Notes about The Definitive Guide to DAX</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/09/personal-notes-about-dax-definitive-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/09/personal-notes-about-dax-definitive-guide/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: this will be a long, long post, written in my own way. It’s essentially a dump of my personal notes, taken when reading “The Definitive Guide to DAX” written by Alberto Ferrari and Marco Russo. At my new workplace I’m going to use PowerBI and DAX a lot, thus my boss suggested me to read the book.&#xA;Yep, it is big and very technical, with 700+ pages rich in contents, but trust me, that’s the “Bible”, a must-read for anyone willing to work with PowerBI and DAX.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My surreal experience with COBOL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/09/my-surreal-experience-cobol/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/09/my-surreal-experience-cobol/</guid>
      <description>I was feeling curious&amp;hellip; So, I decided to challenge myself and try to learn a bit more about COmmon Business-Oriented Language aka COBOL, invented in 1959 by IBM. It’s not the most popular among programmers, being extremely old and with huge limitations compared to today’s modern languages&amp;hellip; Yet, as we will see, it’s still alive, hidden in huge legacy codebases in the form of spaghetti code and difficult to get rid of without an entire system redesign.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First time with Tailwind CSS: showing off my books!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/06/my-books-tailwind/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/06/my-books-tailwind/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m back with another post, this time exploring a new CSS framework, Tailwind CSS!&#xA;In the previous months I started using Angular and Typescript for some small web apps and dashboards, but I always found CSS management cumbersome. I could spend hours tweaking font-size and align-items parameters and hard-coding variables, and this wasn&amp;rsquo;t a lot of fun.&#xA;That&amp;rsquo;s why I decided to try Tailwind, which is being heavily recommended by many people in the frontend community!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Personal Airflow - How I&#39;m monitoring my scripts with Python, Appsmith and SQL Server</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/03/personal-airflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/03/personal-airflow/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the story of how I created my first full-stack project for monitoring my daily activities, using Python and SQL Server in backend and Appsmith for the GUI. I have a lot to learn and process yet, but hey, it&amp;rsquo;s a start.&#xA;😟 The Problem There are scripts I&amp;rsquo;m using that are particularly tedious to monitor. The typical structure is the following:&#xA;Load data (from a file or manual input) Send a request to internal DB / very specific API Compare the data received with the input and if something is wrong, notify me or a colleague.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using a Neural Network for sending memes to my girlfriend</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021/05/nn-sending-memes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021/05/nn-sending-memes/</guid>
      <description>Well, my GF&amp;rsquo;s tastes in memes are simple: she loves wholesome memes and, most importantly, she loves animals.&#xA;That&amp;rsquo;s why I created a fun little project that:&#xA;Surfs the subreddit r/wholesomemes using the reddit API Downloads a few of the hottest memes in the contents folder Initializes a ResNet50 model that recognizes images containing any animal Sends them via mail to my GF (positively welcomed) Final email (3 memes by default) Reddit I&amp;rsquo;m using the praw library for downloading the memes, it requires a Reddit Bot enabled.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
