<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Soft-Skills on Mutt0-ds Notes</title>
    <link>https://mutt0-ds.github.io/tags/soft-skills/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Soft-Skills on Mutt0-ds Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mutt0-ds.github.io/tags/soft-skills/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A MUST for Multi-cultural Teams: The Culture Map</title>
      <link>https://mutt0-ds.github.io/posts/2024/09/the-culture-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mutt0-ds.github.io/posts/2024/09/the-culture-map/</guid>
      <description>Cultures can be very different One of my favorite lessons in my international master&amp;rsquo;s course was about cultural differences. I remember our instructor showing us funny videos of different cultures interacting. There was an American asking an Indian colleague if they&amp;rsquo;ll meet next week&amp;rsquo;s deadline. The response, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll see what I can do&amp;rdquo; could mean either &amp;ldquo;sure&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;no way&amp;rdquo; depending on the cultural context. Needless to add that the American was very confused when the deadline wasn&amp;rsquo;t met the week after.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal Notes about Simply Said</title>
      <link>https://mutt0-ds.github.io/posts/2024/07/personal-notes-simply-said/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mutt0-ds.github.io/posts/2024/07/personal-notes-simply-said/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Simply Said&amp;rdquo; is the best communication book I&amp;rsquo;ve read recently. I discovered it thanks to Jordan Cutler (who runs an amazing tech newsletter) and at first, I considered it a standard communications book. Things like &amp;ldquo;listen to others,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;be positive,&amp;rdquo; blah blah.&#xA;I was wrong. &amp;ldquo;Simply Said&amp;rdquo; is much more than that. That&amp;rsquo;s why I condensed most of its wisdom into this blog post, and I hope it will inspire you to read it as well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal Notes about Presentation Patterns</title>
      <link>https://mutt0-ds.github.io/posts/2023/01/personal-notes-about-presentation-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mutt0-ds.github.io/posts/2023/01/personal-notes-about-presentation-patterns/</guid>
      <description>Presentation Patterns Written by Neal Ford, Matthew McCullough and Nathaniel Schutta, &amp;ldquo;Presentation Patterns - Techniques for Crafting Better Presentations&amp;rdquo; is an encyclopedia of patterns, tips and common mistakes experienced by the authors, who have delivered thousands of presentations. In particular, they introduce “No Fluff, Just Stuff“, a traveling technical conference series covering a wide variety of topics related to software development and management.&#xA;During the years, they have build up their toolbox of patterns to provide killer presentations, which are divided in three main sections: Prepare (thinking and setting up the presentation’s key concepts), Build (creating the slides), Deliver (present the content).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
